Guide to the Boswell Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1672-1850; Series II; 12.25; (30 boxes)
  - Boswell, William (C 548.5-548.52), 1829 (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Boswell family (C 550), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Boufflers, S. J.: verses (C 551-552), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - Bourgeois, Sir Peter (C 553-554), 1794 (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - Bowles, William (C 555-562), 1785-87 (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Boyd, Edward (C 562.7-562.8), 1748, 1750 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Boyd, Hugh (C 563), 1769 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Boyd, Jane (C 564), 1769 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Boyle, David Boyle, Lord (C 566), 1811 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Boyse, Samuel (C 567-568), 1731 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Bradyll, William (C 569), 1791 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Brechin: Burgess ticket (C 569.7) (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Brenan, Michael (C 570), 1768 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Brewster, James (C 571), 1788 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Brian, William (C 572), 1794 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - British Institution (C 573), 1813 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Britton, George Henry (C 574-575), 1785 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Broad, Mary (C 576), 1794 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Broadhead, Mary (C 577), 1791 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Brocklesby, Richard (C 578-583), 1784-85 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Brooksbank, Stamp (C 584), 1791 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Brown, Charles (C 585), 1768 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Brown, James (C 586), 1767 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Brown, Mungo (C 587), 1786 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Brown, Rev. Robert (C 588-595), 1764-69 (Box 18, Folder 387)
  - Brown, Thomas (C 596), 1790 (Box 18, Folder 388)
  - Brown, William (C 597-599), 1767, 1790 (Box 18, Folder 388)
  - Bruce, James
    See also: Series XVII, Boxes 168-169
    - Correspondence (C 600-665), 1763-89 (Box 18, Folder 389-97)
    - "Auchinleck Journal" (C 665.5), 1783-84 (Box 18, Folder 398-401)
    - "Observations on the weather" (C 665.6), 1788-89 (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Bruce, John (C 666), 1785 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Bruyn, Martinus de (C 667-669), 1767-70 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Brydges, Sir Samuel Egerton (C 670), 1815 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Buccleuch, Charles William Henry Montagu Scott, 4th D. of (C 671-671.3), 1813-16 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - Buchan, David Stuart, 11th E. of (C 672-675), 1766-89 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - Buchan, John (C 676), 1785 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Buller, Mary Coxe (C 677), 1785 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Burgess, Sir James Bland (C 678-679), 1791-1818 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Burgoyne, Gen, John (C 680-681), 1778, 1790 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Burke, Edmund (C 682-697), 1775-95 (Box 18, Folder 406-08)
  - Burnaby, Rev. Andrew (C 699-703), 1767-78 (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - Burnet, A. (C 704), 1764 (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - Burney, Charles (C 705-707), 1791-94 (Box 18, Folder 410)
  - Burney, Frances (C 708), 1780 (Box 18, Folder 410)
  - Burns, Robert (C 709), 1759 (Box 18, Folder 411)
  - Bute, John Stuart, 3rd D. of (C 710-713), 1763-81 (Box 19, Folder 412)
  - Bute, John Stuart, 4th E. of (C 714-719), 1765-93 (Box 19, Folder 413)
  - Butler, Charles (C 720), 1795 (Box 19, Folder 414)
  - Byng, John (C 721), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 414)
  - Caldwell, Andrew (C 723), 1769 (Box 19, Folder 414)
  - Caldwell, Rev. Samuel (C 724-729), 1769 (Box 19, Folder 415)
  - Cambridge, Richard (C 730-731), 1790, 1793 (Box 19, Folder 416)
  - Campbell, Amelia Ramsay, Lady (C 732-733), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 416)
    (including Tinker 307)
  - Campbell, Sir Archibald (C 737), 1783 (Box 19, Folder 416)
  - Campbell, Arthur (C 738), 1795 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Campbell, Bruce (C 739.6-740), 1792-93 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Campbell, George James (C 741), 1786 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Campbell, Hugh Bruce (C 791.1), 1856 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Campbell, James, of Treesbank (C 742-744), 1772-75 (Box 19, Folder 418)
  - Campbell of Treesbank family: memorandum (C 745), 1707 (Box 19, Folder 418)
  - Campbell, John (C 746), 1780 (Box 19, Folder 419)
  - Campbell, John, LL.D (C 747), 1775 (Box 19, Folder 419)
  - Campbell, John, M.D. (C 748), 1789 (Box 19, Folder 419)
  - Campbell, Rev. John (C 749-750), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 419)
  - Campbell, M? (C 451), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 420)
  - Campbell, Mary Montgomerie (C 752, 754), 1766, 1769 (Box 19, Folder 420)
  - Campbell, Thomas (C 755), 1785 (Box 19, Folder 420)
  - Cannon, Horatius (C 756), 1788 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Canning, George (C 756.4), 1817 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Capper, Peter (C 758), 1769 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Carlisle, Frederick Howard, 5th E. of (C 759), 1789 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Carlyle, Alexander (C 760), 1788 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Carmichael, "Poll" (C 761-762), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Casabianco, Francesco (C 763), 1790 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Casabianco, Gian (C 764), 1765 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Castlereagh, Robert Stewart, V. (C 765-765.2), 1818-20 (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Cator, John (C 766-769), 1791-94 (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Catt, Henri Alexandre (C 770), 1764 (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Cawthorne, Joseph (C 771), 1769 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - Casenove, Clàviere et fils (C 772), 1764 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - Cesarotti, Melchiore (C 773-773.1), 1765 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - Chaillet, Jean F. (C 774-775), 1764 (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Chalié, Francis (C 776), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Chalmer, John Muir (C 777), 1767 (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Chalmers, Alexander (C 778-778.2), 1795, 1806 (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Chalmers, James (C 779), 1768 (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Chalmers, Margaret (C 780), 1783 (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Chambers, Frances, Lady (C 781), 1795 (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Chambers, Sir William (C 782), 1792 (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Chapman, Joseph (C 783), 1786 (Box 19, Folder 427)
  - Chapone, Hester (C 784), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 427)
  - Chatham, William Pitt, 1st E. of (C 785-786), 1766-67 (Box 19, Folder 428)
  - Churton, Ralph (C 787-789), 1792-93 (Box 19, Folder 428)
  - Clark, Richard (C 790), 1788 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Clarke, Godfrey Bagnal (C 791), 1765 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Cleland, John (C 792), 1776 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Clough, Mrs. Marian (C 794), 1795 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Cobb, Mary Hammond (C 795-797), 1784-89 (Box 19, Folder 430)
  - Cochrane, Basil (C 798-805), 1762-86 (Box 19, Folder 431)
  - Cochrane, Elizabeth (C 806), 1740 (Box 19, Folder 432)
  - Cochrane, Lady Grizel (C 807), 1767 (Box 19, Folder 432)
  - Cochrane, Lady Mary Bruce: "Dream" (C 808), 1713 (Box 19, Folder 432)
  - Cole, Charles Nelson (C 810), 1767 (Box 19, Folder 433)
  - Colquitt, Edward (C 811), 1761? (Box 19, Folder 433)
  - Colville, Elizabeth, Lady (C 812-815), 1767-88 (Box 19, Folder 433)
  - Compton, James (C 816), 1790 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Conant, Nathaniel (C 817), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Conran, George Balfour (C 818), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Constantin, J. B. (C 819), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Conway, Henry Seymour (C 820), 1782 (Box 19, Folder 435)
  - Cooper, Allan (C 821), 1792 (Box 19, Folder 435)
  - Cooper, Rev. David (C 822-824), 1741 (Box 19, Folder 435)
  - Corsica: documents, 1755-90, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 436)
  - Cosway, Maria Cecilia Louisa (Hadfield) (C 833), 1785 (Box 19, Folder 437)
  - Cotton, Harriet: lock of hair (C 834), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 437)
  - Courtenay, John (C 836-844), 1787-92,1811 (Box 19, Folder 438)
  - Coutts, John, and Co. (C 845), 1768 (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Coutts, Thomas (C 846), 1793 (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Craig, James (C 847), 1787 (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Craigie, Robert (C 848), 1748 (Box 19, Folder 439)
  - Cramond, Hercules (C 849), 1787 (Box 19, Folder 440)
  - Crauford, James (C 850), 1766 (Box 19, Folder 440)
  - Crauford, John W. (C 851), 1789 (Box 19, Folder 440)
  - Crauford, Sir Patrick (C 852-853), 1764 (Box 19, Folder 441)
  - Crauford, Thomas (C 853.2-853.3), 1792 (Box 19, Folder 441)
  - Crawford, Jean (Hamilton), Countess of (C 854-860), 1778-90 (Box 19, Folder 442)
  - Creed, John (C 861), 1745 (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Crocchi, Pietro (C 862), 1769 (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Croft, Herbert (C 863-864), 1784 (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Crowe, William (C 865), 1785 (Box 19, Folder 443)
  - Cullen, Charles (C 866), 1791 (Box 19, Folder 444)
  - Cullen, William (C 867), 1784 (Box 19, Folder 444)
  - Cummyng, James (C 869), 1785 (Box 19, Folder 444)
  - Cuninghame, Annie (C 871), 1779 (Box 19, Folder 445)
  - Cuninghame, David (C 872-873), 1787 (Box 19, Folder 445)
  - Cuninghame, James (C 874-881), 1779-92 (Box 20, Folder 446)
  - Cuninghame, Sir John (C 874-881), 1768, 1773 (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - Cunningham, James (C 884), 1734 (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - Currie, Charles Douglas (C 885), 1788 (Box 20, Folder 448)
  - Cust, Francis Cockayne: "Cursory Remarks on the Life of Savage" (C 886), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 448)
  - Cuttoli di Cothi, Chevalier de (C 887), 1789 (Box 20, Folder 448)
  - Dalling, Sir John (C 888), 1792 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Dalrymple, Andrew (C 888.32), 1791 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Dalrymple, Rev. William (C 889-889.2), 1792 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Dance, George, the younger (C 890-891), 1795 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Davel, Theodore (C 892), 1767-68 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Davidson, John (C 893-894), 1768, 1793 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Davies, Jonathan (C 895), 1793 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Davies, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas (C 896-909), 1766-91 (Box 20, Folder 451-52)
  - Dawson, Alexander (C 910-915), 1790-95 (Box 20, Folder 453)
  - Deans, William (C 916), 1779 (Box 20, Folder 454)
  - De Coetlogon, Charles Edward (C 917-918), 1792-93 (Box 20, Folder 454)
  - DeLaval, Daniel (C 919), 1769 (Box 20, Folder 454)
  - DeLaval, Sir John Hussey DeLaval (C 920-921), 1795 (Box 20, Folder 454)
  - Deleyre, Alexandre (C 922-928), 1765-67 (Box 20, Folder 455)
  - Dempster, George (C 929-954), 1763-91 (Box 20, Folder 456-59)
  - Dibden, Charles (C 955), 1769 (Box 20, Folder 460)
  - Dick, Sir Alexander (C 956-999), 1766-85 (Box 20, Folder 461-65)
  - Dick, Sir John (C 1000-1035), 1765-90 (Box 20, Folder 466-69)
  - Dick, Sir William (C 1936), 1779 (Box 20, Folder 470)
  - Digby, (Lettice Fitzgerald), Lady (C 1037), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 470)
  - Digges, West (C 1038-1042), 1759-63 (Box 20, Folder 470)
  - Dilly, Charles (C 1043-1060), 1779-95 (Box 20, Folder 471-72)
  - Dilly, Edward (C 1061-1076), 1767-79 (Box 20, Folder 473-74)
  - Dilly, John (C 1077), 1790 (Box 20, Folder 473-74)
  - Divry, Mlle. A.? (C 1078-1089), 1791 (Box 20, Folder 475-76)
  - Dodd, James William (C 1090), 1793 (Box 21, Folder 477)
  - Dodsley, James (C 1091), 1786 (Box 21, Folder 477)
  - Donaldson, Alexander (C 1092), 1786 (Box 21, Folder 477)
  - Douglas, Archibald James Edward Douglas, 1st Baron of Douglas (C 1093-1098), 1769-87 (Box 21, Folder 478)
  - Douglas, John, Bishop of Salisbury (1100-1106), 1790-94 (Box 21, Folder 479)
  - Downie, William (C 1107), 1794 (Box 21, Folder 480)
  - Doyle, John (C 1108), 1792 (Box 21, Folder 480)
  - Doyle, William: "The Universal Religion" (C 1109), 1785? (Box 21, Folder 481)
  - Dreghorn (John Maclaurin), Lord (C 1110-1112), 1770-91 (Box 21, Folder 482)
  - Drummond, George Home (C 1113), 1786 (Box 21, Folder 482)
  - Drummond, William (C 1114), 1767 (Box 21, Folder 482)
  - Dumbarton: Burgess ticket (C 1114.7)
  - Dumfries, Margaret (Craufurd), Countess of (C 1115-1119), 1773-88 (Box 21, Folder 483)
  - Dumfries, Patrick Macdowall-Crichton, 6th E. of (C 1120-21), 1783 (Box 21, Folder 484)
  - Dun, Alexander Boswell (C 1122), 1792 (Box 21, Folder 484)
  - Dun, John (C 1123-1129), 1766-91 (Box 21, Folder 485)
  - Dunbar, George (C 1130), 1790 (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - Dunbar, James Murray (C 1131), 1765 (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - Duncan, James (C 1131.1), 1766 (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - Dundas, Henry (C 1132-1152), 1768-94 (Box 21, Folder 487-90)
  - Dundas, Lady Jane (Hope) (C 1153), 1793 (Box 21, Folder 491)
  - Dundas, Sir Lawrence (C 1154), 1781 (Box 21, Folder 491)
  - Dundas, Robert (C 1154.8-1156), 1755-69 (Box 21, Folder 491)
  - Dundonald, Jean (Stuart), Countess of (C 1157), 1780 (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Dunfermline: Burgess ticket (C 1157.3) (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Dunlop, Frances Anne (C 1157.5), 1793 (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Dunlop, Susan (C 1158-1159), 1786-89 (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Dunsinnan (Sir William Nairne, Bt.), Lord (C 1150), 1764 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - Dupont, Pierre Loumeau (C 1162-1165), 1766-67 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - Dutens, Louis (C 1166), 1771 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - Eardley, Selena (C 1167), 1792 (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Eardley, William (C 1168), 1794? (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Eden, William (C 1170), 1774 (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Edinburgh: birth registrations (C 1171-1173), 1775-78 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  - Edinburgh Defensive Band, 1782 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - "Eduardo" (C 1175), 1763 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - Edwards, Richard (C 1176-1178), 1767 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - Eglinton, Alexander Montgomerie, 10th E. of (C 1179-1182), 1762-63 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - Eglinton, Archibald, 11th E. of (C 1183-1184), 1789 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - Eglinton, Hugh Montgomerie, 12th E. of (C 1184.5), 1818? (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - Eglinton, Susanna, Countess of, 1768 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - Elcho, Francis-Wemyss, Lord (C 1185.5), 1822 (Box 21, Folder 498)
  - Elcho, Sir John Scott, 1st E. of (C 1185.6-1185.7), 1807-09 (Box 21, Folder 498)
  - Elford, Sir William (C 1186-1188), 1792 (Box 21, Folder 498)
  - Elibank, Patrick Murray, 5th Lord (C 1189-1190), 1773 (Box 21, Folder 499)
  - Eliot, Edward Craggs-Eliot, 1st B. of St. Germans (C 1191-1192), 1791-92 (Box 21, Folder 499)
  - Elphinstone, John Elphinstone, 11th Lord (C 1193-1194), 1785-86 (Box 21, Folder 500)
  - Erroll, James Hay, 15th Lord (C 1196), 1774 (Box 21, Folder 500)
  - Erskine, Andrew (C 1199-1215), 1764-93 (Box 21, Folder 501-03)
  - Erskine, Henry (C 1216-1217), 1788-90 (Box 21, Folder 501-03)
  - Erskine, James (C 1218), 1784 (Box 21, Folder 501-03)
  - Erskine, Sir James St. Clair (C 1219), 1786 (Box 21, Folder 501-03)
  - Erskine, John (C 1220=1220.3), 1791-93 (Box 21, Folder 505)
  - Erskine, Thomas (C 1221), 1786 (Box 21, Folder 506)
  - Exeter, Brownlow Cecil, 9th E. of (C 1222), 1792 (Box 21, Folder 506)
  - Fairlie, Alexander (C1223-1235), 1779-93 (Box 22, Folder 507-08)
  - Falmouth, George, 4th Viscount (C 1236), 1792 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Farington, Joseph (C 1237-1238), 1794 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Farquhar, Alexander (C 1239), 1767 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Fawcett, John (C 1240), 1792 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Fergusson, James (C 1241-43), 1768, 1789 (Box 22, Folder 510)
  - Ferguson, Joseph (C 1243.9-1247), 1766-90 (Box 22, Folder 510)
  - Fife, James Duff (C 1248-1250), 1785-93 (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Finck, Friedrich (C 1251), 1764 (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Findlay, Robert (C 1251.2), 1792 (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Finlayson, John (C 1252-1253), 1774 (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Fitzgerald, Mrs. Mary (C 1254-1263), 1790-94 (Box 22, Folder 512)
  - Fitzgerald, William Thomas (C 1264), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Fitzherbert, William (C 1264), 1767 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Fitzpatrick, Richard (C 1266), 1783 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Forbes, Sir William (C 1267-1303), 1775-95 (Box 22, Folder 514-20)
  - Forbes and Co. (C 1310-1312), 1782-94 (Box 22, Folder 521)
  - Forth, Samuel (C 1313), 1819 (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Foulis, Sir James (C 1314), 1775 (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Foulis, Robert (C 1315-1320), 1767-68 (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Fox, Charles James: inscription (C 1321), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Frazer, George (C 1322), 1766 (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Frederick Augustus, Duke of York (C 1322.3), 1818 (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Froment, Denis Daniel de (C 1323-1324), 1764-66 (Box 22, Folder 524)
  - Froment, Marie de (C 1325-1327), 1767-79 (Box 22, Folder 524)
  - Fullarton, William (C 1328-1329.2), 1779-92 (Box 22, Folder 525)
  - Gallini, Sir John (C 1330), 1792 (Box 22, Folder 525)
  - Galloway, Alexander, 6th E. of (C 1330.2-1330.81), 1748-62 (Box 22, Folder 526-528)
  - Galloway, Catherine, Countess of (C 1330.9), 1749 (Box 22, Folder 526-528)
  - Gambier, John (C 1331), 1795 (Box 22, Folder 529)
  - Gardner, Anne (C 1332-1333), 1791-93 (Box 22, Folder 529)
  - Garforth, John Baines (C 1334), 1789 (Box 22, Folder 529)
  - Garrick, David (C 1335-1352.2), 1764-78 (Box 22, Folder 530-532)
  - Gascoigne, Charles (C 1353-1354), 1769-71 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Gaspari, Count Belleval (C 1355), 1793 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Gaubius, Jerome David (C 1356), 1764 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Gayashuta: speech, ca. 1790 (Box 23, Folder 534)
  - Gayot, Felix Louis (C 1358-1360), 1766 (Box 23, Folder 534)
  - Geelvinck, Catherina Elisabeth (C 1361), 1764 (Box 23, Folder 535)
  - Gentili, Antonio (C 1362), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 535)
  - Gentleman, Francis (C 1363-1369), 1764-74 (Box 23, Folder 536)
  - Gibb, Andrew (C 1369.2-1369.9), 1792-1826 (Box 23, Folder 537-38)
    See also: Series XVII, Box 169, folders 2942-49, and Series XVIII, Box 174, folders 3072-73
  - Gibb, William (C 1390-1391), 1786-94 (Box 23, Folder 539)
  - Gifford, John, and Gordon, James (C 1392) (Box 23, Folder 539)
  - Gilkie, James (C 1393), 1767 (Box 23, Folder 539)
  - Gillespie, Thomas (C 1374-1275), 1784-87 (Box 23, Folder 540)
  - Gillibrand, Richard (C 1376), 1765 (Box 23, Folder 540)
  - Glasgow: Burgess tickets (C 1376.3- C 1376.4)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver (C 1377-1378), 1769,1773 (Box 23, Folder 541)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver: Song, 1773 (Box 23, Folder 542)
  - Goodall, Joseph (C 1380-1382), 1790-91 (Box 23, Folder 543)
  - Gordon, Charles (C 1383), 1763 (Box 23, Folder 543)
  - Gordon, George (C 1384), 1784 (Box 23, Folder 543)
  - Graeme, William (C 1385), 1765 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Graham, George (C 1386), 1779 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Graham, Janet (C 1387), 1766 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Grant, the Misses (C 1388), 1791 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Grant, Lewis (C 1389-1392), 1785-89 (Box 23, Folder 545)
  - Greene, Edward Burnaby (C 1396), 1770 (Box 23, Folder 546)
  - Greene, Richard (C 1397-1399), 1787-89 (Box 23, Folder 546)
  - Greenhill, Thomas (C 1400), 1774 (Box 23, Folder 546)
  - Grenville, William, 1st B. (C 1401), 1795 (Box 23, Folder 547)
  - Gronovius, Abraham (C 1403.8-1404), 1764 (Box 23, Folder 547)
  - Guiffardière, Charles de (C 1405-1407), 1763-64 (Box 23, Folder 548)
  - Guiguer, Juliana (C 1408), 1791 (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Gunning, John (C 1409), 1793 (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Guthrie, Harry (C 1410-1411), 1776 (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Haden, Mrs. S. (C 1412-1413), 1792-93 (Box 24, Folder 550)
  - Hailes (Sir David Dalrymple, Bt.), Lord (C 1414-1479), 1763-91 (Box 24, Folder 551-57)
  - Haldane, Patrick (C 1480), 1748 (Box 24, Folder 558)
  - Hall, Thomas (C 1481), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 558)
  - Hall, Walter (C 1482), 1793 (Box 24, Folder 558)
  - Hamilton, Alexander (C 1483), 1786 (Box 24, Folder 558)
  - Hamilton, Gavin (painter) (C 1484), 1768 (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Hamilton, Gavin (writer) (C 1485), 1783 (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Hamilton, J. (C 1486), 1794? (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Hamilton, John (C 1488-1489), 1783 (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Hamilton, William (C 1490), 1779 (Box 24, Folder 560)
  - Hamilton, William Gerard (C 1491-1493), 1793?, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 560)
  - Harcourt, Mary Danby (C 1494-1495), 1785 (Box 24, Folder 561)
  - Harrington, Charles Stanhope, 3rd E. of (C 1496), 1791 (Box 24, Folder 561)
  - Harris, William (C 1497-1498), 1768 (Box 24, Folder 561)
  - Harrison, Thomas: passport (C 1499), 1765 (Box 24, Folder 561)
  - Hart, John (C 1500), 1785 (Box 24, Folder 562)
  - Harwich Paquet Boat (C 1501), 1763 (Box 24, Folder 562)
  - Harwood, Thomas (C 1502), 1782 (Box 24, Folder 562)
  - Hastings, Warren (C 1503-1506), 1790-91 (Box 24, Folder 563)
  - Hatfield, John (C 1507), 1785 (Box 24, Folder 564)
  - Hawkesbury, Charles Jenkinson, 1st B. (C 1508-1509), 1790-91 (Box 24, Folder 564)
  - Hawkins, Sir John (C 1510-1511), 1783, 1788 (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Hawtrey, Frances (C 1512), 1792 (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Hawtrey, Lucy (C 1513-1514), 1791-92 (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Hay, George, Bp. of Daulis (C 1515), 1779 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Hay, Robert, a friend of (C 1516), 1767 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Hayley, William (C 1519-1520), 1784-85 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Heberden, William (C 1521), 1784 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Hector, Edmund (C 1522-1531), 1785-91 (Box 24, Folder 567-68)
  - Hermenches, David (C 1532), 1764 (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Herrie, Phebe (C 1533), 1780 (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Heron, Lady Elizabeth (C 1534), 1795 (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Herries, Cochrane and Co. (C 1535-1536), 1765 (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Hervey, William Thomas (C 1537), 1786 (Box 24, Folder 570)
  - Hoggan, James (C 1540-1541), 1769 (Box 24, Folder 570)
  - Holt, John (C 1542), 1791 (Box 24, Folder 570)
  - Home, David (C 1543-1544), 1782-83 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Home, John (C 1545), 1821 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Honywood, Sir John (C 1546), 1795 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Hoole, John (C 1547-1550), 1783-93 (Box 24, Folder 572)
  - Hope, John (C 1551-1553), 1794 (Box 24, Folder 572)
  - Howard, Sir George (C 1555), 1787 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Howatson, Andrew (C 1556), 1769 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Howe, Richard Howe, 1st E. of (C 1557), 1786 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Howse, Samuel (C 1558), 1791 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Hübner, Carl Friedrich? (C 1560), 1765-66 (Box 24, Folder 574)
  - Hume, David (C 1562-1563), 1763, 1768 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - Hunter, Andrew (C 1563.4-1563.5), 1792-93 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - Hunter, John (C 1563.7), 1792 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - Hunter, Robert (C 1564), 1763 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - Hunters and Company (C 1565), 1794 (Box 24, Folder 576)
  - Huntly, George Gordon (C 1565.3-1566), 1811-12 (Box 24, Folder 576)
  - Hussey, John (C 1568-1569), 1784, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 576)
  - Hussey, Rev. Thomas (C 1570-1572), 1791-94 (Box 24, Folder 577)
  - Hutton, George Henry (C 1573-1575), 1789 (Box 24, Folder 577)
  - Hutton, James (C 1576), 1792 (Box 24, Folder 577)
  - Impey, Elijah Barwell (C 1577-1579), 1797-1811 (Box 24, Folder 578)
  - Inchiquin, Nary (Palmer), Countess of (C 1580), 1794 (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - Inchiquin, Murrough, 5th E. of (C 1581), 1791 (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - Inner Temple (C 1582), 1761 (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - Inverary: Burgess ticket (C 1582.7)
  - Inverkeithing: Burgess ticket (C 1582.8)
  - Inverness: Burgess ticket (C 1583)
  - Itinerary Berlin-Suisse (C 1584), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - James, Charles (C 1585), 1792? (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - James, Sir Walter James, Bt. (C 1586), 1785 (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - Jamieson, John (C 1586.2), 1820 (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - Jephson, John (C 1588), 1814 (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - Jephson, Richard Mounteney (C 1589), 1787 (Box 24, Folder 581)
  - Johnson, Alexander (C 1591-1592), 1792 (Box 24, Folder 581)
  - Johnson, Richard (C 1593), 1794 (Box 24, Folder 581)
  - Johnson, Samuel
    - Verse fragment (C 1594), 1725? (Box 25, Folder 582)
    - Notes on Norris (C 1595), 1743? (Box 25, Folder 583)
    - Letter to the Earl of Chesterfield (C 1596), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 583)
    - Notes (C 1597-1597.1), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 583)
    - Letter to Mrs. Thrale (C 1597.2), 1773 (Box 25, Folder 584)
    - Inscription for portrait of Mary, Queen of Scots (C 1598), 1775? (Box 25, Folder 585)
    - Advertisement (C 1600), 1775 (Box 25, Folder 585)
    - List of towns (C 1602), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 585)
    - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds (C 1603), 1781 (Box 25, Folder 586)
    - Legal notes (C 1604), 1781 (Box 25, Folder 586)
    - Juvenalia: copies (C 1606), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 587)
    - Letter to Joseph Simpson (C 1607), 1759 (Box 25, Folder 588)
    - Letter to John Taylor (C 1608), 1763 (Box 25, Folder 588)
    - Prayer (C 1609), 1781 (Box 25, Folder 588)
    - Obituary of Coleborn Hancock (C 1610), 1783 (Box 25, Folder 588a)